Guide to the Julie Braun-Vogelstein Collection, 1743-1971 AR 25034 / MF 473
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
- Series IV: Julie Braun-Vogelstein, undated, 1800s-1900s
  - (29/2): Julie Braun Newspaper Clippings re Adam Trott von Solz Ploit to assassinate Hitler, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 239)
  - (29/3): Julie Braun Julie Braun Newspaper Clippings re Adam Trott von Solz, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 240)
  - (30/1): Julie Braun Correspondence Hasso von Seebach, 1934-1941 (Box 27, Folder 241)
  - (30/2): Julie Braun Correspondence Hasso von Seebach + Relatives, 1944-1946 (Box 27, Folder 242)
  - (30/30: Julie Braun Correspondence Hasso von Seebach and Friends, 1946-1948 (Box 27, Folder 243)
  - (30/4): Julie Braun Correspondence Hasso von Seebach and friends, 1949-1951 (Box 27, Folder 244)
  - (31/1): Julie Braun Correspondence Hasso von Seebach and relatives, 1952-1958 (Box 27, Folder 245)
  - (31/2): Julie Braun Correspondence Hasso von Seebach and friends, 1959-1963 (Box 27, Folder 246)
  - (31/3): Julie Braun Correspondence Hasso von Seebach, 1961-1964 (Box 27, Folder 247)
  - (32/1): Julie Braun Correspondence Alice de Witt Stettin, 1923-1935 (Box 27, Folder 248)
  - (32/2): Julie Braun Correspondence Alice de Witt Stettin, 1936-1937 (Box 27, Folder 249)
  - (32/3): Julie Braun Correspondence Alice de Witt Stettin, 1937-1938 (Box 27, Folder 250)
  - (32/4): Julie Braun Correspondence Alice de Witt Stettin, 1934-1945 (Box 27, Folder 251)
  - (32/5): Julie Braun Correspondence Alice de Witt Stettin, 1940-1953 (Box 27, Folder 252)
  - (33/1): Julie Braun Letters to Alice Stettin, 1950-1953 (Box 28, Folder 253)
  - (33/2): Julie Braun Letters to Alice Stettin and Manuscript presented, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 254)
  - (33/3): Julie Braun Letters of JV-B to Alice Stettin, 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 255)
  - (33/4): Julie Braun Letters of JVB to Alice Stettin, 1958-1960 (Box 28, Folder 256)
  - (33/5): Julie Braun Letters of JVB to Alice Stettin, 1961-1962 (Box 28, Folder 257)
  - (33/6): Julie Braun Articles re Heinrich Braun sent to Alice Stettin, 1932 -1933 (Box 28, Folder 258)
  - (33/7): Julie Braun Partial Manuscript on art by JVB dedicated to Alice de Witt Steetin, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 259)
  - (34/1): Julie Braun Correspondence Adler, Emmy, Fritz, Felix, 1903-1949 (Box 28, Folder 260)
  - (34/2): Julie Braun Correspondence Adler-Aschner, including Hannah Arendt, 1944-1970 (Box 28, Folder 261)
  - (34/3): Julie Braun Correspondence Cohn, Erica + Ludwig O, 1945-1968 (Box 28, Folder 262)
  - (34/4): Julie Braun Correspondence David, Hermine, 1923; 1926-1949 (Box 28, Folder 263)
  - (34/5): Julie Braun Correspondence Day, Helen + Dixon H., 1963-1971 (Box 28, Folder 264)
  - (34/6): Julie Braun Correspondence Demio, 1920-1932 (Box 28, Folder 265)
  - (34/7): Julie Braun Correspondence DeMan, Dr. Hendrik (Crossref. Heinrich Braun), 1926 -1933 (Box 28, Folder 266)
  - (35/1): Julie Braun Correspondence B, 1931; 1957-1971 (Box 28, Folder 267)
  - (35/2): Julie Braun Correspondence Bagley, Charles + Kien, 1959-1971 (Box 28, Folder 268)
  - (35/3): Julie Braun Correspondence Bandler, Wyllis, 1950-1954 (Box 28, Folder 269)
  - (35/4): Julie Braun Correspondence Bandler, Wyllis, 1955-1957 (Box 28, Folder 270)
  - (35/5): Julie Braun Correspondence Bandler, Wyllis, 1958-1962 (Box 28, Folder 271)
  - (35/6): Julie Braun Correspondence Bandler, Wyllis, 1963-1970 (Box 28, Folder 272)
  - (35/7): Julie Braun Correspondence Banzer, Do Do, 1964-1967 (Box 28, Folder 273)
  - (35/8): Julie Braun Correspondence Banzer, Do Do, 1968-1971 (Box 28, Folder 274)
  - (36/1): Julie Braun CorrespondenceBelke, Ingrid, 1965-1971 (Box 28, Folder 275)
  - (36/2): Julie Braun Correspondence Bergstrasser, Benning Hoff, + von Berg, 1933-1967 (Box 28, Folder 276)
  - (36/3): Julie Braun Correspondence Bodley, Bonhoeffer, 1963-1970 (Box 28, Folder 277)
  - (36/4): Julie Braun Correspondence Boller, Boveri, 1964-1971 (Box 28, Folder 278)
  - (36/5): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Brecht, Arnold and Clara, 1922-1942; 1961-1970. (Box 29, Folder 279)
  - (36/6): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Burdach, 1919-1938 (Box 29, Folder 280)
  - (37/1): Julie Braun, Correspondence, E, 1931-1934; 1953-1971 (Box 29, Folder 281)
  - (37/2): Julie Braun, Correspondence, F, 1933-1939; 1963-1971 (Box 29, Folder 282)
  - (37/3): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Frank-Fahler, Guenther, 1927; 1952-1970 (Box 29, Folder 283)
  - (37/4): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Fries, Marlene and Heinz, 1954-1957. (Box 29, Folder 284)
  - (37/5): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Fries, Marlene and Heinz, 1958-1970. (Box 29, Folder 285)
  - (37/6): Julie Braun, Correspondence, G, 1958-1970 (Box 29, Folder 286)
  - (37/7): Julie Braun, Correspondence, G, 1927-1928; 1958-1970 n.R. (Box 29, Folder 287)
  - (37/8): Julie Braun, Correspondence,Goloman Gretel, 1928-1948 (Box 29, Folder 288)
  - (37/9): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Groetz, Dr.Alfred, 1956-1971. (Box 29, Folder 289)
  - (37/10): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Greenberg, Gruenwald, 1959-70 (Box 29, Folder 290)
  - (38/1): Julie Braun, Correspondence, H, 1927-1932; 1961-1970. (Box 29, Folder 291)
  - (38/2): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Baerbel von Haerten, 1959-1970 (Box 29, Folder 292)
  - (38/3): Julie Braun, Correspondence, von Hofacker, von Haerten, L. von Moltke also Photos (children), 1965-1970 (Box 29, Folder 293)
  - (38/4): Julie Braun, Correspondence,Haas, Hopkinson, 1950-1970 (Box 29, Folder 294)
  - (39/1): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Hohenfriser, Nelly, 1922,1940-1959. (Box 29, Folder 295)
  - (39/2): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Hohenfriser Nelly, 1960-1962 (Box 29, Folder 296)
  - (39/3): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Hohenfriser Nelly, 1963-1965 (Box 29, Folder 297)
  - (39/4): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Hohenfriser Nelly, 1966-1971 (Box 29, Folder 298)
  - (39/5): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Holzman, 1926-1927 (n.R.) (Box 29, Folder 299)
  - (39/6): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Heffermann, Marianne von, 1956-1958 (Box 29, Folder 300)
  - (40/1): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Isenberg, Gerda and Ikli, Carl, 1924; 1939-1968. (Box 30, Folder 301)
  - (40/2): Julie Braun, Correspondence, J, 1958-1968 (Box 30, Folder 302)
  - (40/3): Julie Braun, Correspondence, K, 1961-1970 (Box 30, Folder 303)
  - (40/4): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Kurz Isolde, 1923-1936. (Box 30, Folder 304)
  - (40/5): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Lentz Georg, 1967-1971 (Box 30, Folder 305)
  - (40/6): Julie Braun, Correspondence, L, 1950; 1959-1969 (Box 30, Folder 306)
  - (41/1): Julie Braun, Correspondence, M, 1931; 1961-1970. (Box 30, Folder 307)
  - (41/2): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Malbranc, Gabriele, 1934-1971 (Box 30, Folder 308)
  - (41/3): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Maas, Mayer., 1948-1970 (Box 30, Folder 309)
  - (41/4): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Meinecke (Box 30, Folder 310)
  - (41/5): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Natorp, Helene, 1928-1935 n.R. (Box 30, Folder 311)
  - (41/6): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Neumark, Neumann, Prof. Carl Noalk, 1919-1935; 1961-1971 n.R. (Box 30, Folder 312)
  - Julie Braun, Correspondence, Neumark, 1967-1970; 1986 n.R. (Box 30, Folder 313)
  - (42/1): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Gertrude Oppenheimer and Ruth, 1920-1937; 1958-1962. (Box 30, Folder 314)
  - (42/2): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Gertrude Oppenheimer and Ruth, 1963-1967 (Box 30, Folder 315)
  - (42/3): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Gertrude Oppenheimer and Ruth, 1968-1971. (Box 30, Folder 316)
  - (42/4): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Osten-Sacken, 1958-1970 (Box 30, Folder 317)
  - (43/1): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Pfauter Karl, 1956-1970 (Box 30, Folder 318)
  - (43/2): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Plessner Monika and Helmuth, 1960-1963. (Box 30, Folder 319)
  - (43/3): Julie Braun, Correspondence,, Plessner Monika and Helmuth, 1964-1970 (Box 30, Folder 320)
  - (43/4): Julie Braun, Correspondence, R, 1934; 1957-1970 (Box 30, Folder 321)
  - (43/5): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Rosenbloch-Huessey, Eugen, 1944-1966 (Box 30, Folder 322)
  - (43/6): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Rademacher Hans, 1957-1960 (Box 30, Folder 323)
  - (43/7): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Rademacher Hans, 1961-1967 (Box 30, Folder 324)
  - (43/8): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Rademacher Irma, 1957-1969 (Box 30, Folder 325)
  - (43/9): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Sabertsky, Sachs (Box 30, Folder 326)
  - (44/1): Julie Braun, Correspondence, Schaeder, Schwerins, 1933-1970 (Box 30, Folder 327)
  - (44/2): Julie Braun: Correspondence Schliette, Ruth and Heinz, 1967-1969 (Box 31, Folder 328)
  - (44/3): Julie Braun: Correspondence Schliette, Ruth and Heinz, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 329)
  - (44/4): Julie Braun: Correspondence Simon, Ernst and Uriel, 1948-1966 (Box 31, Folder 330)
  - (44/5): Julie Braun: Correspondence Schelika, Renata von., 1960-1971 (Box 31, Folder 331)
  - (44/6): Julie Braun: Correspondence Schelika, Renata v., 1954-1958. (Box 31, Folder 332)
  - (45/1): Julie Braun: Correspondence S, 1960-1970 (Box 31, Folder 333)
  - (45/2): Julie Braun: Correspondence Spiegielberg, Marie-Louise, 1953-1961. (Box 31, Folder 334)
  - (45/3): Julie Braun: Correspondence Spiegielberg Marie Louise, 1962-1964. (Box 31, Folder 335)
  - (45/4): Julie Braun: Correspondence Spiegielberg Marie Louise, 1965-1966. (Box 31, Folder 336)
  - (45/5): Julie Braun: Correspondence Spiegielberg Marie Louise, 1967-1969 (Box 31, Folder 337)
  - (45/6): Julie Braun: Correspondence Staudinger, Hans and Else, Stranz, Rudolf, Stransky Lu, 1959-1969. (Box 31, Folder 338)
  - (45/7): Julie Braun: Correspondence Strecker, Gabrielle, Stolpier, Toni, Sykes Christopher, 1960-1971. (Box 31, Folder 339)
  - (45/8): Julie Braun: Correspondence Stettin, Alice DeWitt, 1931-1963. (Box 31, Folder 340)
  - (45/9): Julie Braun: Correspondence Stettin, Alice de Witt, 1964-1978 (Box 31, Folder 341)
  - (46/1): Julie Braun: Correspondence Thimme Analise, 1959-1963 (Box 31, Folder 342)
  - (46/2) Julie Braun: Correspondence Thimme Analise, 1963-1970 (Box 31, Folder 343)
  - (46/3): Julie Braun: Correspondence von Trott Doris and Clarita, 1950-1969 (Box 31, Folder 344)
  - (46/4): Julie Braun: Correspondence von Trott Barbara and Heinrich and Clarita als T, 1935; 1960-1970 (Box 31, Folder 345)
  - (46/5): Julie Braun: Correspondence Treuenfels Rudolf and Peter, 1957-1965. (Box 31, Folder 346)
  - (47/1): Julie Braun: Correspondence Ullmans-Wurzmans, 1927-1970 (Box 31, Folder 347)
  - (47/2): Julie Braun: Correspondence Zerner, Zimmerman, Zucker and Zwirner, 1956-1971. (Box 31, Folder 348)
  - (48/1): Julie Braun, empty Envelopes from Otto and Heinrich Braun, 1889-1920 (Box 32, Folder 349)
  - (48/2): Julie Braun, Birthday Telegramsn, 1967-1968 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 350)
  - (48/3): Julie Braun, Obituaries, Julie B-Vogelstein and Alice DeWitt Stettin, incl. negatives, 1968-1971 (Box 32, Folder 351)
  - (48/4): Julie Braun L.V. Bequest to and Paintings to Metropolitan Museum, Correspondence and Photographs, 1928-1934 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 352)
  - (48/5): Julie Braun, Otto Braun, Taufschein v. Julie Braun V and Heinrich Braun, Documents, 1906-1919 (Box 32, Folder 353)
  - (48/6): Julie Braun, Aus Meinem Leben by Kaethe Kolwitz, x erw x p.119, Correspondence, 1917. (Box 32, Folder 354)
- Series V: Heinemann and Rosa Vogelstein, undated, 1800s-1900s
  - (1/1): Heinemann-Rosa Vogelstein JB-V Correspondence, 1891-1920. (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - (1/2): Heinemann-Rosa Vogelstein JB-V Correspondence, 1913-1919 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - (1/3): Heinemann-Rosa Vogelstein JB-V Correspondence, 1912-1914 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - (1/4): Heinemann-Rosa Vogelstein JB-V Correspondence, 1910-1914 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - (1/5): Heinemann Vogelstein Correspondence, 1868-1891 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - (1/6): Israel and Julie Vogelstein (Heinemann's parents), 1868-1891 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - (1/7): Heinemann-Rosa Vogelstein Album, 1861-1867 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - (1/8): Heinemann-Rosa Vogelstein Manuscript, Correspondence with Organisations, 1884-1908 (n.R.) (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - (1/9): Heinemann Vogelstein Rabbinical Material, 1831-1910 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - (1/10): Heinemann Vogelstein Liberales Judentum etc, 1897-1911 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - (2/1): Heinemann Vogelstein Death notices, 1911 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - (2/2) Heinemann Vogelstein Lectures, 1911 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - (2/3): Heinemann Vogelstein Lectures, 1917 n.R (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - (2/4): Heinemann Vogelstein Lectures, n.d. n.R. (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - (2/5): Heinemann Vogelstein Correspondence, Rosa, Julie Braun-V., 1886-1900; 1910 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - (2/6): Heinemann Vogelstein Sermons, Exam, n.d. n.R. (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - (2/7): Heinemann Vogelstein Documents in Hebrew, 1743, 1770, 1847-1898 n.R (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - (2/8): Heinemann and Rosa Vogelstein Miscelaneous, includ. Reminiscences by Rosa re. Heinemann, 1864-1911 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - (2/9): Heinemann and Rosa Vogelstein re.Heinemann, 1864-1911 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - (2/10): Heinemann and Rosa Vogelstein re Heinemann, 1897-1906 n.R. (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - (3/1): Heinemann Vogelstein Sermons, 1894-1895 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - (3/2): Heinemann Vogelstein Sermons., 1902-1910 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - (3/3): Heinemann Vogelstein Sermons., 1901 + on n.R. (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - (3/4): Heinemann Vogelstein Sermons., 1880-1909 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - (3/5): Heinemann Vogelstein Sermons., 1902-1911 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - (3/6): Heinemann Vogelstein Sermons., 1901-1910 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - (3/7): Heinemann Vogelstein Sermons., 1898-1911 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 27)
  - (4/1): Rosa Vogelstein Correspondence, Dr. Porges, 1867-1920 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 28)
  - (4/2): Rosa Vogelstein Correspondence, Reports, Lectures, etc., 1894-1915 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 29)
  - (4/3): Rosa Vogelstein Correspondence, Reports, Lectures, etc, 1915-1918 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 30)
  - (4/4): Rosa Vogelstein Correspondence, Heinemann, Vogelstein, 1879-1916 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 31)
  - (4/5): Rosa Vogelstein Correspondence, Hermine Schmidt Lahron, n.d n.R. (Box 33, Folder 32)
  - (4/6): Hermann Vogelstein, Synagogue Materials, 1902-1958 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 33)
  - (4/7): Hermann Vogelstein,, Correspondence, Julie Braun-V., 1898-1941 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 34)
- Series VI: Von Kretschman/Von Gusted Branch, undated, 1800s-1900s
  - (1/1): Hans von Kretschmann, Army Correspondence, to his wife, 1866-1871 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - (1/2): Hans von Kretschmann, Army Correspondence, 1870-1871 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - (1/3): Hans von Kretschmann, Army Correspondence, 1870- n.R. (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - (1/4): Hans von Kretschmann, Army Correspondence, 1864; 1870 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - (1/5): Hans von Kretschmann, Army Correspondence, 1870-1871 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - (1/6): Hans von Kretschmann, Army Correspondence, 1870 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Mascha (mother) Lilly (sister), Department of Justice File, 1918-1919 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Mascha (mother) Lilly (sister), Department of Justice File, 1919-1922 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Auto Biography 127 p., 1918 n.R. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - (2/1): Jenny von Gustedt, Correspondence etc., 1876-1924 n.R. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - (2/2): Jenny von Gustedt, Miscelaneous, 1841-1924 n.R. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - (2/3): Jenny von Gustedt, Correspondence Ottilie von Goethe, 1828-1859 n.R. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - (2/4): Jenny von Gustedt, Correspondence, Jenny von Kretchman (daughter), 1866-1890 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - (2/5): Jenny von Gustedt, Correspondence, Lilichen Lily von Kretschman (granddaughter), 1868-1890 n.R. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - (2/6): Jenny von Gustedt, Correspondence, Walter and Wolfgang von Goethe, 1835-1881 n.R. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - (2/7): Jenny von Gustedt, Correspondence, 1810-1850 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - (2/8): Jenny von Gustedt, Correspondence, 1919-1932 (n.R.) (Box 34, Folder 17)
  - (2/9): Jenny von Gustedt, Correspondence, to Clarchen, 1841; 1881-1889 n.R. (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - (2/10): Jenny von Gustedt, Correspondence, Journal, Day books, 1825-1881 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - (2/11): Jenny von Gustedt, Correspondence to Empress Augusta, 1882-1889 and; 1864-1882. (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Heinrich and Lily Braun, Correspondence, Copies in Bundes Archiv-Koblenz, 1900-1910. (Box 34, Folder 21)
- Series VII: Addenda, undated
  - Addenda (not microfilmed), undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Addenda (not microfilmed), undated (Box 36, Folder 1)